A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Other Secondary Sources Relevant to RIMR/RU History FA852
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Other Secondary Sources Relevant to RIMR/RU History
1952-2001
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
FA852
1 box(es) 1 box
1 box.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 897
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of the RAC.
Scope and Contents
Content spans both the Rockefeller Institute and Rockefeller University eras.
Women; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Medicine, Preventive; Biochemistry; Life sciences; Science -- Study and teaching; Medical sciences; Women's history; Biology -- Research; Architecture; Medical research; Medical education
- Gray, Christopher, "Neighborhood/New York's Most Elegant Sidestreet" Avenue, vol. 6, no. 7, April 1982, 11 pp, 1982 April (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Alexenberg, M., "Aesthetic Experience in Creative Process" Bar Ilan University Press, Israel, (interviews with Sam Granick, Mark Kac, and Paul Weiss) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Cranefield, Paul F., "The Neuron" (verses written on the occasion of the 1952 Cold Spring Harbor Symposium on Quantitative Biology) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Silverstein, Arthur M., "The History of Immunology" in William E. Paul, ed., Fundamental Immunology (New York: Raven Press, 1984), 23-40 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Berliner, Howard S., A System of Scientific Medicine: Philanthropic Foundations in the Flexner Era (New York and London: Tavistock Publications, 1985) (excerpts) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- "The New Neurons in a Canary's Brain" Newsday, 4 October 1988 (re the work of Fernando Nottebohm and Arturo Alvarez-Buylla's work at Millbrook, NY), 1988 October 4 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Lyon, Peter, "The Rockefeller Institute" Holiday (September 1964), 53-54, 56, 108-109, 114-115, 1964 September (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Garfield, Eugene, "Ninety-One Citation Classics from the Journal of Experimental Medicine" Current Comments, no. 12, 13 July 1987, 3-13, 1987 July 13 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Rosenfield, R.E., "Who Discovered RH? A Personal Glimpse of the Levine- Wiener Argument" Transfusion, vol. 29, no. 4, 355-357 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Bendiner, Elmer, "Louise Pearce: A 'Magic Bullet' for African Sleeping Sickness" Hospital Practice, vol. 27, no. 1, 15 January 1992, 207-221, 1992 January 15 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Bäumler, Ernst, "Sein Ruhm kam erst in der Neuen Welt: Karl Landsteiner entdeckte nicht nur die Blutgruppen" in Herz & Gefässe, 13 (2/1993), 85-87, 1993 February (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Summers, William C., "On the Origins of the Science in Arrowsmith: Paul de Kruif, Felix d'Herelle and Phage" Journal of the History of Medicine and Allied Sciences, vol. 46, no. 3, July 1991, 1991 July (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Schlesinger, R. Walter. Virus Research at the Princeton Rockefeller Institute, 1930-1945: Recalling a Wellspring of Discoveries. Infectious Agents and Diseases, vol. 1, no. 6, 1992, pp. 325-337 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Kingsley, Sidney. "Why I Didn't Write This Play: Sidney Kingsley on J. Robert Oppenheimer" The New Theater Review. 11, Fall 1994, 17-21 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Hess, J.R., Schmidt, P.J. The First Blood Banker: Oswald Hope Robertson. Transfusion. 40, January 2000, 110-113, 2000 January (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Gray, Christopher. From a Child's Death Came a Medical Institute's Birth. The New York Times. February 25, 2001, LI-RE 9, 2001 February 25 (Box 1, Folder 16)